# **Ivan Symchych**

Software Engineer from Lviv, Ukraine

**Email:** ivan.symchych@gmail.com

Github: isymchych

LinkedIn: ivansymchych

#### **SUMMARY**

Full-stack software developer with 11 years of experience, seeking interesting projects.

A systems thinker, pragmatic, result-oriented. I enjoy finding simple solutions to complicated problems. Know about clean code, teamwork, documentation, and tests.

Committed to professional growth.

**Not interested** in gambling, bets, user tracking, or ads industries.

## **TECHNICAL HIGHLIGHTS**

- TypeScript, JavaScript, Rust, Java, SQL, GraphQL
- HTML, CSS, SCSS, CSS-in-JS
- OOP/OOD, FP, Design Patterns, SOLID, HTTP, REST
- Linux, Emacs

I'm an expert in TypeScript and JavaScript, love and enjoy Rust, and, earlier in my career, used to code in Java. Last few years I was working primarily with Node.js, React/Redux, GraphQL, REST, HTML, SCSS, CSS-in-JS, and a bit of Angular.

Also, I have experience with HTML5 video streaming and WebRTC.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Consultant at Remit**

April 2016 - February 2021

#### Web Frontend for MaginePro, a video streaming company

MaginePro is a white-label OTT platform. I helped to build the single-page application in React and prerendering server in Node.js. Application is highly customizable via feature flags and scales for multiple partners, which could be configured on the fly.

Also, I was working on a cross-platform video player, Chromecast receiver application, introduced end-to-end tests, and automated internal processes.

React, Redux, Fela, Typescript, Node.js, GraphQL

#### Calendar application for ThinkTank, the platform for collective intelligence

Single page calendar application for managing events and appointments using REST API in Java. I took part in both frontend and backend development.

Angular, TypeScript, RxJS, SASS, Java, Spring

# Consultant at SoftServe

August 2015 - April 2016

#### Jitsi Meet for Atlassian

 $I \ was \ refactoring \ and \ fixing \ bugs \ in \ the \ Jitsi.org \ web \ app, \ an \ open-source \ video \ conferencing \ solution.$ 

ES6, Babel, Lodash, JQuery

#### HipChat for Atlassian

I was working on React-based web UI for HipChat, a chat for teams from Atlassian. I took part in refactoring, bugfixing, and writing unit and integration tests.

ES6, React, Lodash, Karma, Selenium

#### Java/JavaScript developer at Intellias

July 2012 - August 2015

#### Secure online chat peer.me for Tenios, a German VoIP service provider

Webchat leverages the power of WebRTC, cutting-edge technology which allows browsers to communicate with each other without a server (peer-to-peer), with end-to-end encryption. I was working on JS library which encapsulates core functionality like sending encrypted text messages and files, synchronizing data between clients, establishing group audio and video calls. Also, I took part in the development of SPA UI and backend.

Java, WebSockets, WebRTC, Marionette.js, Tomcat, Jasmine

## Web portal and utilities for Tenios, a German VoIP service provider

The web portal is a SPA for customers to manage their phone numbers, routing plans, bills, calls forwarding, etc., and an admin portal to manage customers and internal business processes. The backend was implemented as a REST API. I took part in both frontend and backend development.

Java, Spring, Hibernate, PostgreSQL, Marionette.js, Bootstrap

#### Web portal for RPLab, diagnostic laboratory from Belgium

Web frontend for ETL process on client medical data. As a result, the system also generates per-client reports in HTML or pdf formats. I took part in both frontend and backend development.

Java, Spring, MongoDB, JSP, Stripes, FlyingSaucer, JFreeChart

#### Java Developer at JSC Kredobank

July 2010 - July 2012

#### Web services to aggregate and simplify internal business processes

I was working on design, development, bugfixing, and support of internal web services. Also, I built a GUI client in Swing for those web services.

Java, JBoss, SOAP, WSDL, Oracle 11g, Jenkins CI, Gradle

#### **EDUCATION**

Master's degree in Applied Mathematics, Ivan Franko National University Of Lviv, Ukraine, 2007 - 2013

#### **LANGUAGES**

English Advanced

**Ukrainian** Native

Russian Limited working proficiency

#### **INTERESTS**

programming, science fiction & popular science, traveling, hiking, computer games